-Let's go. -He's so cute!
-走吧 -好可爱喔
Papy!
小巴比
You don't have to work as a police dog today, so relax!
你今天不用当警犬 所以放轻松点吧
KIICHI SEGAWA
（营业部 濑川希一）
Please call if you're interested.
静候您的回复
Yes!
太好了…
MIKI TIRES
（三木自行车）
-You're early. -I came straight from work.
-你很早啊 -从医院直接过来了
-Sorry to have kept you waiting. -Welcome, Keebou!
-让你久等了 -希少 欢迎回来
-Thanks. -Hey!
-谢谢 -我来
Oh.
你…
-Why? -I don't know. Why are you here?
-他怎么会在？ -不知道
You can let her stay the night here too.
你让她晚上在这边也没关系的
That would be asking too much of you, but thanks.
要你们照顾她那么久 不太好意思 不过谢了
Thank you, too, Kayo.
也谢谢你了 小佳代
Look, Keebou.
希少 你看
What have you made? A rabbit?
你折了什么？兔子？
It's scary!
好恐怖
-It's a female demon.
-是般若
And we had stewed beef for lunch!
然后午餐吃了炖牛肉
Kayo made it for you?
真的？小佳代弄的？
Mikki did.
是米奇
I'm impressed.
他还真厉害
It was absolutely delicious.
真的超好吃的
-Was it? -Yeah.
-是啊？ -对
But I like the fried eggs you make too.
不过你的荷包蛋也很好吃
-Do you? -Yeah.
-是吗？ -是啊
It's all right, don't worry about hurting my feelings.
行了 不用怕伤了我的心
Keebou, this…
希少 这个…
How may I help you?
找我有什么事？
Mr. Segawa!
濑川先生？
-Why? -This is my home.
-为什么？ -这里是我家啊
Oh, no! I got the wrong place.
讨厌 我弄错地方了
-I was wondering why I can't open it. -Actually, that isn't the question.
-难怪门不开 -问题不是那个
You…
你…
I just moved here today.
我今天刚搬来这里
Seriously?
-什么？真的假的？ -真的
-Yes. -Wow, it's a miracle! Like in a drama.
这简直是奇迹 像在演戏
This isn't a coincidence you see in a drama nowadays.
我觉得现在的连续剧 也不会有这种巧合
Oh…
对啊…
Oh!
啊！
Is she the girl you were looking for the other day?
她该不会是你之前在找的…
Yes, she is.
就是她
Sorry for the trouble we caused that day.
上次真的不好意思
I'm glad to know she is safe.
你没事就太好了
Hello.
你好
Are you living with her?
你们一起住吗？
There is a reason for that.
对 因为某个原因…
Owing to the complicated circumstances,
情况很复杂
we have to live together.
我们没办法才一起住
What do you want for supper? Anything you want?
晚餐吃什么？有什么想吃的吗？
Oh!
对了
Shall I invite our neighbor?
问一下隔壁的要不要一起吧
To celebrate her house move.
当作庆祝她新居入伙
Oh?
怎么了？
She has come to invite us for dinner?
难道是她来约我们了？
Well, of course not…
怎么可能…
Mr. Kiichi Segawa?
是濑川希一先生吗？
Yes.
我是
I'm an officer from Numazu Chuo Police Station.
我是沼津中央警察局的警察
Yes?
什么？
It's already so late?
已经这么晚了？
Please stay a bit longer.
拜托 再多陪我一下
I'm so lonely.
人家很寂寞
When you're with me you're still lonely anyway.
你跟我一起 结果还是会寂寞吧？
I'm sorry.
对不起…
-The formula of loneliness. -What?
-寂寞的方程式 -什么？
It's more lonely when you're with me and you want to leave
跟你一起 但你却要离我而去
than when we're apart but you are thinking of me.
比你在远处 我却想着你更加寂寞
What did you say?
你…在说什么？
Frankly, I don't get this. I have never understood.
说真的 我从来没明白过
Understand what?
明白什么？
Stuff like loneliness.
寂寞什么的
Are you not lonely when I'm not with you?
就算我不在你身边 你也不会寂寞吗？
If I say I'm not lonely you'll tell me you'll die again.
如果我现在说不寂寞的话 你又会说要去死了 对吧？
Don't phrase it like that.
你别那样说
Are you not lonely?
你不寂寞吗？
-Yes, I am. -The body found was…
-寂寞啊 -发现的尸体
Numazu Chuo Police Station Criminal Investigation Division's
是沼津中央警察局刑事科的警部补
assistant inspector, Mr. Tatsuhiko Akagi, 56 years old. At 3 p.m. today
赤城达彦 56岁
a man strolling along the embankment found him and called the police.
一名在河堤散步的男子 在发现尸体后报警
There you are!
找到你了
Have you seen the television?
你有看电视吗？
There is no way I have watched the TV, is there, Manager?
店长 看也知道我没看电视吧
-He was killed! -What?
-他好像被杀掉了 -什么？
The policeman who referred you to this job.
是那个介绍你来的警察
Pichan, please let me buy it!
小皮 求求你 让我买
Please!
让我买
But Saya, do you use ventriloquism?
可是纱彩 你懂腹语吗？
VENTRILOQUISM PUPPET, CHAPPY
（腹语人偶恰比）
Yes I do!
我会的
I will practice it! I'll work very hard.
我会努力的 纱彩会练习的
But you can use the nutcracker to do this. Its mouth can move.
那个…你用胡桃钳练习腹语吧 它的嘴巴也能动
You're right.
也对…
It clicks when it moves.
它会咯咯地响
To me this is already…
纱彩有这个…
enough.
就够了？
Okay, got it. Buy it then.
我知道了 按下去吧 买吧
Thank you, Pichan! I love you!
小皮 谢谢你 我爱死你了
Do you love me, Pichan?
小皮 你爱不爱我？
Silly!
傻瓜
-I really love you. -According to the police
-我最爱你了 -根据警方表示 发现的尸体
Numazu Chuo Police Station Criminal Investigation Division's
是沼津中央警察局刑事科的警部补
assistant inspector, Mr. Tatsuhiko Akagi, 56 years old.
赤城达彦 56岁
I'm home.
我回来了
-Have you heard, Noriaki? -Yes?
-典明 你听说了吗？ -什么？
There was a murder on the embankment in front of us.
在前面的河堤发生了命案
Seriously?
真的假的？
A customer told me just now.
是刚才客人告诉我的
And the killer?
犯人呢？
They haven't caught the killer.
他说犯人还没抓到
Is it someone in the neighborhood?
不知道是不是附近的人做的… 典明 怎么办？我好害怕
Don't worry. They'll find the murderer soon.
没事的 犯人很快就会被抓到的
You'll protect me and the children because you're strong, right?
典明你这么厉害 一定会保护我跟宝宝的吧？
I say,
你啊
have you got nowhere else to go?
没别的地方好去了吗？
It's boring here.
你在我这里也很无聊吧？
-But… -You got in my way…
-那个… -你挡住我的路了
You…
那个…
How did you and those guys become friends?
你是怎么跟他们成为朋友的？
-You mean Keebou and the others? -Yeah.
-希少他们吗？ -没错
How did we become friends?
你问我怎么成为朋友？
We just became friends.
就这样啊
How do you just become friends?
什么叫“就这样”？
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Keebou… Keebou was…
希少…希少他…
-So what is wrong? -The police took him away!
-你告诉我 他怎么了？ -他被警察带走了
I'll ask you again.
我再问你一次
Why was this found at the crime scene?
为什么这个会掉在现场？
KIICHI SEGAWA
（营业部 濑川希一）
What? You're cocky enough to use your right to remain silent?
你干嘛？这么狂妄行使缄默权吗？
-Is it true? -What?
-是真的吗？ -我听不到
Was Mr. Akagi really killed?
赤城先生真的被杀了吗？
Darn!
可恶！
Why…
为什么？
Why was Mr. Akagi…
为什么赤城先生会…
Is it possible that…
难道说…
It was because he let us go?
是因为他放了我们走？
If that's the case…
如果是这样的话
Does that mean Tagawa did it?
那就是田川的所为了？
Ponjara!
碰将 你要去哪里？
Where else? To find Tagawa.
还会是哪里？当然是去找田川
This is stupid.
你疯了？
-Shut up! -Calm down!
-你好烦！ -冷静点！
-What will you do then? -But…
-你去了又能做什么？ -可是…
Mr. Akagi doesn't want us to do that.
赤城先生不会希望你这么做
I don't think Tagawa did it.
我觉得不是田川干的
At that time
那个时候 田川像是 听赤城先生的指挥办事的
So, Mr. Akagi was killed by someone who hired him?
你是说 是利用赤城先生 比他更厉害的人做的？
If so…
如果是这样的话
We should be careful too.
我们也得小心一点才行了
Hey!
你啊
Don't come to my place anymore.
别再来我家了
Why?
-什么？ -你不是我们的同伴
Stay away from other people's business.
别管与你无关的事情
Hey!
等一下
Mikki… You didn't have to be so harsh.
米奇…你不用说得那么过份吧？
Really, that's what I think is not so good about you.
真的 你这方面有点太那个了
He's still a kid.
他还是个小鬼 我不想再连累他
Then you should have said so at the beginning. There you go.
那你为什么一开始不这么跟他说？
-Really? -Yeah.
-是吗？ -对
I'll text him later.
我等一下替你发个短信吧
When did you exchange email addresses with the kid?
你…你是什么时候 跟那小鬼交换信箱的？
What?
什么？
You didn't?
你们没有吗？
Choco!
巧克力…
You're finally popular with guys, too?
你终于也对男的下手了啊？
Hikari.
日花里
Don't worry, Hikari.
日花里 没事的
He was not arrested so he will come back.
又不是被逮捕了 他会回来的
On top of that Keebou didn't do anything,
况且希少什么也没做过
so it's safer for him to stay with the police.
留在警察局反而比较安全
If the worst happens we will all testify for him.
真的有必要的话 我们会好好为他作证的
Don't worry!
真的没事的
The Japanese police are not idiots.
日本的警察又不是笨蛋
You killed him, didn't you?
不是你做的吗？
You were looking for Mr. Akagi
在赤城休假的时候
while he was on his holiday, weren't you?
你不是找过他吗？
We have conclusive evidence.
我们还掌握了决定性的证据
That's impossible.
那怎么可能？
What do you want?
你要做什么？
I'm going home. You asked me to come voluntarily, didn't you?
我要回去了 你们应该没逮捕令吧？
So I can go at any time I want.
所以我应该可以随时离开
-Please go away. -Try getting him away.
-请让一下 -你推开他试试看
I'll arrest you for obstructing the police in the execution of their duties.
我会以妨碍公务罪立即逮捕你
What the heck?
搞什么鬼？
Sit down now!
你快给我坐下
I'll tell you what killing a policeman means to us…
我会好好地让你知道 对我们来说
very thoroughly.
杀警到底是怎么一回事
About the murder happened today in which a policeman was strangled,
在今天发生的现任警察绞杀案中
the police are investigating what Tatsuhiko Akagi was doing beforehand…
警方正在调查 死者赤城达彦死前的行动…
Boss! People from head office are here!
老大 本部的人来了
Tagawa, I have called in.
田川 打扰了
Bring him here.
带他过来
-But he was brought back by the police… -Bring him here.
-可是他被警察… -带他来
I said he was pulled in…
我说了 他被抓去…
Tagawa.
田川啊…
You are as dull as the beer.
你的脑袋跟这啤酒一样糟糕
It seems that you still don't understand…
你好像还没听懂我说的话
This is the reason I come here.
我大老远的过来就是为了这个
If he got the kid, Tagawa…
要是他带走了那小鬼 田川
I won't let you get away with it easily.
我不会轻易放过你
The policeman was killed, you know?
而且那个警察也被杀了
Have some awareness
有点危机意识啊
of a crisis situation.
懂吗？危机意识
-Can you manage? -Yeah.
-可以吗？ -可以
What's the matter? Come in.
怎么了？进来吧
Hikari?
日花里？
Was it my fault?
是我害的吗？
Was it my fault that the policeman was killed?
是我害警察叔叔被杀死的吗？
Of course not.
那怎么可能？
Was it also my fault that Keebou was caught?
希少也是我害他…
-If you stay with me you'll also… -Hikari!
-如果你跟我一起 连你也会… -日花里
I'll tell you…
我告诉你
what you can do for Keebou now.
你现在能为希少做的
You have to be cheerful.
就是要打起精神
You have to be cheerful and smile.
要打起精神 拿出笑容
If you're not smiling when Keebou comes back, he'll be sad.
希少回来的时候 你没有笑的话 他会伤心的
Come on, come inside.
好了 快进来吧
Fold origami with Grandma again tomorrow.
明天再跟奶奶折纸吧
Okay?
好吗？
Good.
好
Come in.
来 进去
MIKI TIRES
（三木自行车）
RITOU
（里岛）
Don't come to my place anymore.
你别再来我家了
You're not one of us.
你不是我们的同伴
What's wrong? What's happened?
什么？怎么了？
Just now…
刚才…
A strange man came…
有个奇怪的男人
-and stole my bra. -Your bra?
-拿了我的胸罩 -胸罩？
Thief!
死小偷！
Stop, pervert!
你别跑 死变态！
Pervert! Give me back the bra!
你这混蛋 把胸罩还给我！
Bra…
胸罩…
This is… a bra.
这就是胸罩啊
You…
我说你
I said, I didn't do it.
我说了 不是我干的
Then who did it?
那是谁干的？
I don't know!
我不知道
Brace up. We can stay here for a long time.
你就快招了吧 我们还能陪你玩很久
Good morning.
两位早
I am his lawyer,
本人是小田岛 是他的律师
Oh?
怎么了？
How do you explain this?
你这是什么意思？
Keebou has not come back.
希少没有回来
No…
就是啊 他在干什么？
Okay! Let's go somewhere.
好 去什么地方走走吧
For a change of mood.
去转换一下心情
-But the shop… -I'll skip work.
-那店里呢？ -旷工
I don't get many customers anyway.
反正也没什么客人来
Where do you want to go?
有想去的地方吗？
Thank you for helping me!
真的得救了
Thank you.
谢谢你
They can't compel you to stay if you came voluntarily.
他们没有逮捕令 是不能强留你的
That was totally against the law.
那完全是违法的
And they were interrogating you in a threatening manner.
他们还用恐吓的方式盘问你
It's something reckless that only the police in the old days did.
这完全是不符时代潮流的暴行啊
But why have you come for me?
但是 律师你为什么会来找我？
They have paid me as well.
他们连钱都付了
What? Really?
什么？是真的？
Those guys… They even did that?
那些家伙居然为我做到这样
-I'm sorry. -Now, now.
-对不起… -好了…
Don't be ridiculous! Are you looking down on me?
你别开玩笑！你这是在小看我吗？
I told you!
我就说了啊
I just went to take the bra back from a pervert!
我只是从个变态的手上拿回胸罩而已
It was our fault.
是我们警察错了
This is the so-called false accusation.
对了 这个是冤案吧？
I'll write about it on Twitter!
我要写在推特上 该死！
-We're sorry… -Toru?
-请你别这样… -透？
Oh? Keebou?
什么？是希少？
METROPOLITAN POLICE STATION
（沼津中央警察局）
They were accusing the innocent!
我真的是无辜的
How dare the policemen look down on me?
真是的 死警察竟然小看我？
Hey…
等一下…够了 快收好那个
RECRUITING POLICE OFFICERS
（警官招募中）
Mr. Segawa, please get in. I'll drive you back.
濑川先生 请上车 我送你回去
Thank you for doing so much.
不好意思 那么麻烦你
-So, I… -I'll drive you back too. Please get in.
-那我… -你也请吧
You'll do that?
什么？可以吗？谢了
Thank you.
麻烦你了
Hey, my friend.
你好啊 朋友
MIKI TIRES
（三木自行车）
Are you okay?
你还好吧？
You don't have to force yourself to remember.
不用强迫自己想
-Mikki. -Yes?
-米奇 -什么事？
Where are your parents?
你的爸爸和妈妈呢？
-Mine? -Yeah.
-我的？ -对
My dad died and my mom ran away.
我爸死了 我妈离家出走了
Before Grandma became like this,
奶奶变成这样之前
she was a frank person,
她是个心直口快
and she used to say everything on her mind.
有什么说什么的人 她倒是没什么恶意的
My mom couldn't stand her.
我妈…好像受不了
-So she ran away from home? -No.
-所以她离家出走了？ -不是
She ran away from home after Grandma became like this.
她是在奶奶变成这样之后才出走的
She thought it was her fault that Grandma went senile.
她觉得奶奶失智是她的错
Her conscious kept blaming her when she saw Grandma,
觉得看到奶奶时 都像是在被她责备
and she wanted to die.
所以很想死
She said…
她说再这样下去
If this continued…
要不是她死
She would either kill herself or Grandma.
就是她会杀掉奶奶
You can't do anything about that.
那也没办法解决了
If that's what she thinks
她自己要那么想的话
nothing can be done, no matter what the other says.
其他人说什么也没用
-But what about you, Mikki? -Yes?
-那你呢？ -什么？
Are you fine with this?
你不在意吗？
I love both Grandmas.
因为两个奶奶我都喜欢
Even though she has forgotten lots of things?
就算她忘记了很多事情也是？
Yes, even so.
就算那样也是
Because she is my grandma.
因为她是我奶奶
Let him go. He is not involved in this.
你让他回去吧 这事情跟他没关系的
Please, Mr. Tagawa.
求求你了 田川先生
I can't just say, "Oh, he isn't?" and let him go, can I?
我不可能说“啊 是吗？” 就放他回去吧？
Mr. Tagawa!
田川先生…
It's too late to do that.
现在已经过了那个阶段了
Too late?
阶段？
That's why I told you to back out of this.
所以我上次才叫你别管了
Hikari! Where have you been?
日花里 你到哪里去了？
Hikari!
日花里
What a relief!
太好了
I've been so worried about you.
老师很担心你啊
But you're all right, aren't you?
但你没事 对吧？
I'm really relieved…
太好了 真的是太好了
Excuse me, who are you?
请问…你是哪位？
That is my line. Who are you?
我才要问你 你是谁？
Hello and welcome.
你们好 欢迎你们
Hey!
好了 你们这些外围组织的人 去外面把风
Yes, sir.
是
Where is the kid?
小鬼在哪里？
Where have you hidden her?
你把她藏在哪里？
Things keep repeating themselves, seriously.
真是的 又来了？
Sorry I keep repeating my answer, but I don't know.
不好意思 我的答案还是一样 我不知道
I heard…
我听说…
your tolerance of pain was high.
你好像很能忍痛
Is she at your friend's place?
是在你同伴那里吗？
I heard you were a local.
你是在这里长大的吧？
There are friends you hang out with, aren't there?
一定有常在一起的同伴吧？
Did you let her stay at someone's place?
是把她放在谁的家了吗？
Toru! Stop it!
透…别这样
I'll easily find that out if I do some digging.
我查一下 很容易就会知道了
If you aren't talking,
如果你不肯说
I'll find them out and ruin their homes one by one.
我就把你的同伴都查出来 再逐一去把他们家都拆了
No! None of them knows this! He knows nothing, too!
不要 他们都不知情 他也一样不知道
Please let us go!
拜托你放他走
You're so annoyingly noisy.
你真的好烦
Hikari has lost her memory?
日花里 你失忆了？
Her parents have disappeared too.
你父母也是下落不明
It must have been scary for you.
你一定很害怕 日花里
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm your class teacher, Ms. Sawako.
我是你的班主任 佐和子老师
Ms. Sawako…
佐和子老师…
That's right.
没错
I've been your teacher since you were transferred here last spring.
你去年转学来之后 我就是你的班主任了
Oh, right.
对了
Look.
你看 是去年去远足时拍的
You see?
你看
So who are you?
我说 你到底是谁？
Who am I?
我是谁…
Well, it's hard to explain…
这…比较难解释
Hikari, come with me to the school
日花里 跟老师回学校 再谈谈以后怎么办吧
I will bring her back and take care of her.
我会负责照顾她的
Well, my friend asked me to take care of her,
不行 我也是朋友拜托我照顾她的
I'll ask him before letting her go with you.
我得先问他一下
Please call him now.
那请你立刻打电话
But it's a bit difficult…
但现在不方便
-Why? -He's at the police station.
-不方便？ -他在警察局
Police?
警察局？
Anyway…
总之
I will take her with me for now.
我先带她走了
Please call me after you call your friend, and confirm it's okay.
你问过你的朋友之后 再打电话给我
Is that all right?
可以吧？
SAWAKO FUJISHIRO
（教师 藤代佐和子）
Can I call your school?
我可以打电话去学校吗？
Go ahead.
随便
Toru!
透
It's too early to sleep, boy!
现在要睡还太早 小子
We'll have a break.
先休息一下
Toru!
透
-Are you all right? -I'm not all right.
-你还好吧？ -一点也不好
I'm sorry for getting you involved.
对不起 连累你了
I see.
是这样吗？
Thank you.
谢谢你
You believe me now?
那你相信了？
Yes. Sorry about that.
是 刚才对不起
It's okay. I was rude as well.
没关系 我才是太没礼貌了
You let Hikari stay with you, but the words I said were so harsh.
你们保护了日花里 我态度却那么差
I was worrying about her, that's why I…
我一直很担心她 所以…
If you have to give a child over to a stranger,
毕竟你要把一个孩子 交给一个素未谋面的人
you should be as careful as you were.
是该谨慎点才恰当
It's all right.
没有的事…
Hikari, come with me.
日花里 跟老师走吧
You're bringing the gentleman trouble.
别给别人添麻烦 日花里
You can't keep bringing trouble to people who aren't close to you.
你不能一直给没关系的人添麻烦的
You didn't bring us trouble. Not at all.
我们一点也不觉得麻烦 真的
Are you sure?
你决定了？
See you, Kayo.
小佳代 再见
See you!
再见
Take care.
好好保重
-Darn! Okay… -Get a good one.
-该死…再来 -来 拿张好的
They won't kill us, will they?
他们应该不会杀了我们吧？
What?
什么？他们会杀了我们？
Who is calling at this hour?
是谁在这时候打来？
You…
等等 你…
Quick!
快点
Turn your back to me.
把你的背转向我
Keebou, not that one.
希少 不是那个
I know! Idiot!
我知道啊 笨蛋
Yes. Can I kill them?
是…那我可以杀了他们吗？
Well, it's going to be the same anyway.
反正结果也会一样
Yeah.
没错
-Tagawa! -Yes?
-田川 -是
Keep an eye on them inside.
你去里面看着他们
You lost. 100,000 yen.
输了…十万
Wow, the bra is nice.
接得好 胸罩
Hey.
快…
Get it using your foot.
用脚拿
Slowly.
慢慢来
Oh, you look so pitiable.
你这样子真可怜
What's wrong with you?
你怎么搞的？
Your contact list is so short!
你联系人名单上没几个人啊
You pretend to be cool but you actually have no friends?
你平时在虚张声势 但其实是孤独一人啊
Who are you going to call when you have no friends?
一个人孤孤单单的 打算要联络谁啊？
You haven't got friends?
你没有朋友吗？
No.
没有
I don't need friends.
我才不需要朋友
-Friends only betray you. -Toru…
朋友反正也会背叛我的
Don't get this wrong.
别弄错了
You don't think of people as friends because they help you.
不是能帮你的才叫朋友
You think of them as friends because you want to help them.
是你想帮助的人 那才叫朋友
TEACHER, SAWAKO FUJISHIRO
（教师 藤代佐和子）
Hey!
我来了
What's up, Choco?
怎么了？巧克力
My customer gave me a piece of chocolate cake.
客人给了我一块巧克力蛋糕
But Choco can't eat chocolate.
巧克力不能吃巧克力吧？
Yeah, so I've brought it here for Hikari.
没错 所以带来给日花里了
Oh?
咦？
Where is Hikari?
日花里呢？
I was hesitant about letting Hikari go with her without asking Keebou.
没问过希少就让日花里跟她走 我也很犹豫
But I guess it's safer that way than staying with us, because they know
不过黑道都认得我们 也知道我们在哪里
who we are and where we live.
她和那老师一起会比较安全
Well, you're right about that.
你说得也是
Speaking of which, he has still not been released…
话说回来 他这么久还没出来
Will he be all right?
没事吧？
But as Tenten said,
不过 像典典说的
maybe it's safer for him to be at the police station now.
现在他在警察那里还比较安全
What is actually going on?
这到底是怎么一回事？
Isn't the matter going to keep getting more serious?
总觉得这件事越来越夸张了
Yeah.
是啊
Anyway, I'll text the guys about Hikari.
总之先给给大家发短信 跟他们说日花里的事
Oh.
那个死小孩给我发短信了
You mean Toru?
你是说透？
What? He is lonely already?
怎么了？这么快就觉得寂寞了
What is this?
这是什么？
I'll get the guys' attention.
我去引开他们的注意力 你趁那空档快逃
Don't be defeated…
千万别输
Toru.
透
Don't be defeated until you win.
在你赢之前 千万别输
Idiot! Don't mind me, just go!
笨蛋 别管我了 快走
You said someone is my friend because I want to help them.
你说我想帮忙的才是朋友吧？
Just go!
你快逃
Hey!
喂！你们两个在干什么？
-Run, idiot! -How dare you?
-笨蛋 快逃 -你这混蛋
You know what the consequences are.
你居然敢逃跑？
Brat!
-看我的！ -去死吧！
Mr. Tagawa, please!
田川先生 求求你
Please let him go!
放过他吧
I can't do that, even though it's a request from my friend.
办不到 就算是朋友的请求也一样
Stay still.
乖乖地待在这里
I think the guys will come soon.
他们应该快会到了
I sent his photo along with your location to them.
我把他的照片和位置情报 一起发出去了
This is my territory.
这里是我的地方
They act too self-importantly here and it's humiliating.
让那些人在这儿胡乱撒野 我太没面子了
Then do something more helpful!
那你就再多帮我们一点 就这一点没什么用啊
Oh, shut up.
你真烦
This is the most I can do.
我现在能做的只有这么多
Chancellor.
总长
Thanks.
谢谢
Don't worry.
没事了
They won't come.
不会来的
-Why? -It was my phone and where I am.
-什么？ -是我的手机跟我的照片吧？
-They won't come. -They will.
-他们不会来的 -会来的
If he sent a photo of you beaten-up so badly.
他发了你被揍得很惨的照片
They would if it were your photo.
如果是你的 他们当然会来
But I…
可是我…
I'm not one of them.
我不是他们的同伴
Why? You are our friends.
为什么？你也是同伴吧？
No, I'm not.
不是同伴
He made it clear.
他说得很清楚
Let's make a bet.
要打赌吗？
Yes?
什么？
An intestine set meal.
赌注是内脏定食 要打赌吗？
-That's cheap. -They will come.
-还真便宜 -他们会来的
They will.
他们一定会来
Of course they won't come here.
不会的 他们不可能会来
They'll never come here for someone like me!
他们根本不可能会来救我
What are you mumbling?
你们在那边窃窃私语什么？
Let's begin our second round.
来进行第二轮吧
THE ORION
（猎户座）
-Great picture. -I'll do the next one.
-拍张照吧 -来吧
Hey!
喂！
He really doesn't know anything.
他真的什么都不知道
He has nothing to do with us, find it out from me.
他跟我们没关系 要问就问我吧
He can't tell you anything!
你问他也问不到什么
No! I told you, he knows nothing about this.
别打了！
You know, don't you?
那你是知道的吧？
Tell me now.
快点说出来
I'll kill this boy if you don't.
你不说 我就要杀了这小子了
-Do it. -Yes, sir.
-动手 -是
No!
住手！
I'll tell you.
我说了 别杀他
She is in my apartment.
在我的公寓
There is a closet on the rooftop of my apartment building. She's there.
我公寓的屋顶上有个柜子 她就在那里
Are you telling the truth?
你说的是真的吧？
I am.
是真的
If that was a lie…
要是你敢骗我的话…
I will kill your families, too.
我会杀了你们两个家里所有人
No! She isn't there!
那是假的 她不在那里
Don't harm our families!
你不要伤害我的家人
Please…
求求你
How dare you…
你居然敢愚弄我？
look down on me?
你这该死的家伙
That means, boy,
那就是说 小子
you know where the kid is, too, don't you?
你也知道那小鬼在哪里了？
Good.
好啊
Let's make a deal.
那跟你们做个交易
Before I count to five,
在我数到五之前
I will save the one who tell me where the kid is first.
谁先说了 谁就能安全离开
And the other one?
没说的呢？
I'll bury him.
把他埋了
If both of you don't tell
如果你们两个都不说
I'll bury the two of you together.
我就把你们埋在一起
Then I'll change my plans.
我要改变策略 找出你们的朋友
I'll first look for your friends, and try to get it from them in turn.
然后一个一个地去把小鬼找出来
I don't even need you two.
我不再需要你们了
-Hang on… -One…
-等一下… -一…
Say it, Toru. You can tell him.
说吧 透 跟他说
It's okay.
没关系的
The guys will manage.
他们一定会想办法的
Why are you so confident?
你那信心是从哪里来的？
Because you are friends?
又是因为他们是同伴吗？
-Yeah. -Two!
-没错 -二
I don't believe this.
我根本不相信这些
People betray me because I trust them!
你相信他们 所以他们才会背叛你
Then isn't it easier not to count on anyone right from the start?
那从一开始就不靠任何人 不是更轻松吗？
Yes, perhaps.
可能是吧
That's easier.
那的确是比较轻松
Three!
三！
That was what I thought
在跟他们分开的十年里
in the ten years that I was apart from the guys.
我也是这样想 不过…
But it was really dull.
那实在是很无聊
It's easy when you have no friends, but it's very boring.
没有同伴的确是很轻松 但也很无聊啊
It's boring, but it gives you more freedom.
是无聊 但那不是比较自由吗？
That's not the case!
并不是那样的
I feel freer…
那很自由
with them
比起自己一个人
than on my own.
跟同伴一起更自由
Four!
四！
Toru.
透
Have faith in your friends!
相信你的同伴
No! We are not friends!
不是 不是同伴
None of them needs me!
我在不在 他们也不在乎啊！
I have always been…
从以前开始 我就…
You're not the one to decide that, it's us!
那不是由你来决定 决定的是我们
"Us"? They're not even coming here!
“我们”？但他们没来啊
They won't come! They won't!
不会来的…他们不会来的！
Five!
五！
Who the heck are you?
你们这些家伙是谁？
No way!
不是吧？
Why?
为什么…
Hey, Toru! Are you okay?
透 你没事吧？
Oh?
希少 怎么你也在？
Really…
真的…
They really came for me…
他们真的来救我了…
Who did you say you are?
我在问你们是谁！
Who are you?
-你是谁？
I am…
我是…
myself!
我自己！
Get out of my way, scum!
别挡路 混蛋
Oh, wow, you're here as well, Keebou?
怎么了？希少 你也在啊？
We can kill two birds with one stone!
这是一石二鸟啊
Stop where you are!
你别逃
Gosh! Don't cause us trouble. Okay.
真是的 别给人添麻烦啊 好了
-Keebou. -Thanks.
-希少 -谢了
It's okay. Please go.
没问题的 请你先走
Okay.
好
Thanks for that, Chancellor.
总长 谢谢你帮忙
It wasn't much, though.
虽然只有一点
Aihara, hit me. Now!
相原 打我 快点
-Why? -He's watching.
-什么？ -他在看
He is staring.
他正盯着我们
I'm sorry.
不好意思了
You're in my way!
别挡路
Mikki…
米奇…
Sorry, we were late.
对不起 我们来迟了
He said that he would save us if we talked,
那人说告诉他的话 就能安全回去
but the boy didn't talk at all.
但他到最后还是没说出来
-Well done! -Good boy. You did a great job.
-做得好 -好…你做得很好
See? I told you they would surely come.
我就跟你说了 他们一定会来的
How long are you going to cry?
喂 你还要哭多久？
You're such a cry baby.
真是爱哭鬼
Guys, let's go home.
好了 我们回去了
Toru, you owe me an intestine set meal.
透 你要请我吃内脏定食
That's great. Oh, hold on…
真好…等一下
We came to rescue you, Toru!
来救你的是我们吧 透？
Hey!
怎么搞的？
There you go.
拿去
Are you all right, Melos?
没事吧 梅洛斯？
I'm all right.
我没事
Who is Melos?
梅洛斯是谁？
-Who else if not you? -What?
-除了你还有谁？ -什么？
You kept saying that the guys wouldn't come.
还一直说他们“不会来…”
Melos runs, you know.
梅洛斯是会跑的
You're Melos, starting today.
从今天起 你就是梅洛斯了
Engrave today's joy in your name.
把今天的喜悦都刻在那名字上吧
I will engrave the joy on my heart, but Melos?
我会牢记那喜悦 但梅洛斯…
-Let's make it "Bra", shall we? -I like the name Melos.
-那就叫“胸罩”… -梅洛斯就好了
Good boy.
好
So, now you're formally one of us.
现在你正式成为我们的同伴了
We have no choice but to let you join,
没办法了 只好让你加入
because Keebou gave you a really stupid nickname.
因为希少替你取了个超土的昵称
You mean Keebou gave you all your stupid nicknames?
那大家那些土气的昵称都是希少…
-Hey… -Don't say it's stupid.
-喂… -你别一直说土 好不好？
It's, you know…
这是那个…
The rite of passage.
像成年礼之类的东西吗？
Gosh, Pi. The words you used were so difficult.
怎么了 小皮？说这么难的词
Can you even spell the words?
你汉字写得出来吗？
I can't.
写不出来
What the heck?
你啊…
I see.
这样吗？
Thanks, Mikki.
谢谢你 米奇
It's probably best for Hikari.
我想那对日花里来说是最好的
Sorry for asking you first.
对不起 我擅作主张
It's okay. That's for the best.
不 那样就好
-May I borrow your cellphone? -Sure.
-可以借你的手机吗？ -拿去
Thank you.
谢了
You're calling her right away?
马上就打了吗？
I guess he wants to hear her voice.
他希望听听她的声音吧？
Please answer the phone. I'm busy now.
来 你去替我接电话 我现在很忙
Come on. Answer it.
快点去吧
Sorry, Keebou.
希少 对不起
That woman is no teacher.
那个女人根本不是什么老师
Don't kill me.
不要杀我
We received our next order. Let's go.
收到指令了 我们要出去
Didn't it seem a little off?
她感觉很奇怪 对吧？
I understand.
我们都非常清楚
Your words reached my heart.
我们都懂你要说的话
We'll all go to see you.
我们一定会一起去找你的